# Richard Wilkosz Software Engineer

#### **Phone**

715-370-8005

#### **Email**

richard.w.wilkosz@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/richard-wilkosz-026b4715a

#### GitHub

github.com/richardwilkosz

#### Website

richardwilkosz.com

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Front End

JavaScript
ES6 / TypeScript
Vue.js
Angular
JQuery
REST API integration
HTML / CSS
SCSS / SASS
Bootstrap

### Back End

#### **UX Design**

Responsive design

Accessibility design

Wireframing

Usability testing

### **Project Management**

Git
Jira / Confluence
Agile / Scrum
Unit testing

## **SAMPLE PROJECT**

Check out Ray, my database of movies I own on Blu-ray! It features Vue.js, REST API consumption, and responsive design: richardwilkosz.com

## **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience writing production-level code. Specializes in user-centered front ends, but delivers clean, reusable code throughout the tech stack. In the past year, has demonstrated leadership and communication skills by serving as team Scrum Master and mentoring 5 interns.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Apr 2021 – Present Software Engineer Sentry Insurance

- Designs and implements web application to replace vendor system with millions of data rows. Back end features C# / SQL batch processes with over 70% test coverage. Front end features CRUD data tables and Material Design SCSS framework.
- Mentors 5 interns for the 2021 summer program. Meets weekly to address technical and company-related questions. Coordinates social events and guest speakers to establish connections.

Jan 2020-Mar 2021

## **Software Developer**

Sentry Insurance

- Digitized the company's 2020 United Way donation campaign with a C# web application, processing nearly 4500 transactions.
- Delivered employee health information system, replacing a PeopleSoft component with a C# web application.
- Designed and implemented new front end components for 4 legacy systems, including systems owned by other teams.
- Served as team Scrum Master for over 1 year. Led daily meetings, tracked development progress, and communicated milestones and course corrections to management.

May 2018– Dec 2019

## **Associate Software Developer (Internship)**

Sentry Insurance

- Created functional Angular prototype of an administration page for call flow automation. Conducted 3 user interviews to inform the design and presented the prototype to department executives.
- Delivered C# web application to replace legacy mainframe system, featuring C# / SQL batch processes and CRUD data tables.

Oct 2017-Dec 2019

## **Technology Tutor, Writing Tutor**

University of Wisconsin-Stevens Point

- Tutored over 50 peers in Computer Science courses: Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, and more.
- Tutored over 30 peers in written communication, including business proposals and technical documents.

#### **EDUCATION**

Dec 2019

# **B.S. Computer Information Systems**

University of Wisconsin-Stevens Point

- Double majored in Web Development.
- Graduated summa cum laude.